<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Intelligent management of resources through technology and the methods of science with human and environmental concern.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:23:57 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:23:57 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guide to Copenhagens Community Dinners 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Copenhagen is buzzing with cultural centers and community cafes where people gather to socialize and events are held to raise awareness of community projects. Folkekøkken or community kitchen are community dinners held with a purpose of providing a family style affordable meal to bring people in the community together. The prominence is given to making folkekøkken accessible to everyone and almost always meals are prepared with environment in mind with a vegetarian and vegan option available. Additionally some kitchen are donation based and for some you are welcome to join in for the meal preparation in exchange for a free meal, you can always reach out to organizers for the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the current community kitchens, please make sure to check via the link provided for specific dates of each dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kraftwerkets-vegan-folkekøkken--valby-&quot;&gt;Kraftwerket’s Vegan Folkekøkken ( Valby )&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KraftWerket is a youth club and culture house in Valby and it hosts a community dinner every Tuesday at 18:00. The dinner costs only 25kr, cash only and is almost always Vegan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address: &lt;strong&gt;Valgårdsvej 2, Copenhagen 2500&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/kwfolkekokken&quot;&gt;facebook.com/kwfolkekokken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kafa-x-folkekøkken--nørrebro-&quot;&gt;Kafa-X Folkekøkken ( Nørrebro )&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kafa-X is a food club made up of volunteers that host a community dinner every Tuesday at 19:00. The dinner is donation based with a suggested donation of 20kr, for those that would like to eat for free you can contact the organizers and show up early and help with the preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address: &lt;strong&gt;Korsgade 19, Copenhagen 2200&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/174659825958018&quot;&gt;Kafax Folkekøkken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bumzen-community-kitchen--nørrebro-&quot;&gt;BUMZEN Community Kitchen ( Nørrebro )&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bumzen is a community kitchen that host a dinner every Wednesdays with door opening at 18:00 and food served at 19:00. The dinner is donation based and is almost always Vegan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address: &lt;strong&gt;Baldersgade 20, Copenhagen 2200&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/bumzencommunitykitchen&quot;&gt;facebook.com/bumzencommunitykitchen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kapelvej-44--nørrebro-&quot;&gt;Kapelvej 44 ( Nørrebro )&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kapelvej44 is a local culture house that host community dinners on Tuesdays from 17:00 until 20:00. The dinner is 50 kr for adults and 25 kr for kids and always include a vegetarian option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address: &lt;strong&gt;Kapelvej 44, Copenhagen 2200&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/kapelvej44&quot;&gt;facebook.com/kapelvej44&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;absalon-kirke--vesterbro-&quot;&gt;Absalon Kirke ( Vesterbro )&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absalon is a old church converted into a community venue that hosts community dinners daily. The dinner is hosted at 18:00 and the tickets go on sale at 17:00. The cost is 50 krona, and you can buy the tickets on the spot. Make sure to arrive close to 17:00 since they often sell out fast. The only exception is Fridays where tickets are 100kr and include desert and can be purchase ahead of time through the billeto link on their page. Mondays and Wednesdays the dinners are vegetarian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address: &lt;strong&gt;Sønder Blvd. 73, Copenhagen  1720&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://absaloncph.dk/?page_id=3651&quot;&gt;absaloncph.dk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;onebowl--nordvest-&quot;&gt;OneBowl ( Nordvest )&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Bowl is Copenhagens first “Pay as you feel” community restaurant run by volunteers aiming to provide good food and open to everyone. This mean there are no set prices and rather a suggested donation amount for each menu. The menu is vegan and plant based. You can find out about opening hours on their site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address: &lt;strong&gt;Borups Alle 205, Copenhagen 2400&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.onebowl.dk/&quot;&gt;onebowl.dk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;glad-dinner-at-kube--frederiksberg-&quot;&gt;Glad Dinner at KU.BE ( Frederiksberg )&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KU.BE is a culture house in Frederiksberg hosting community dinners every Wednesday at 17:30. The tickets cost 79 kr for adults and 49 kr for kids under 8 years. They can be bought at the door or reserved beforehand by calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address: &lt;strong&gt;Dirch Passers Allé 4, 2000 Frederiksberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kube.frederiksberg.dk/arrangementer/glad-aftensmad-f%C3%A6llesspisning-hver-onsdag-i-kube&quot;&gt;kube.frederiksberg.dk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/sustainable%20living/pollution/oceans/2019/01/07/guide-to-community-dinners-in-Copenhagen.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/sustainable%20living/pollution/oceans/2019/01/07/guide-to-community-dinners-in-Copenhagen.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Sustainable Living</category>
        
        <category>Pollution</category>
        
        <category>Oceans</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>12 New years resolutions to lower your environmental footprint</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As we have entered the new year most of us have had a chance to reflect on 2018 and think about the changes they want to introduce in 2019. Having experienced a record breaking summer in Denmark and learning so much about the pressing environmental issues of our time have caused many people to strive towards more green lifestyle practices. Although many people have been able to drastically shift their lifestyle and habits, for most people change comes about gradually by taking small steps towards realistically achievable sustainable practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that a lot of the changes not only benefit the environment but can improve your health, finances and overall wellbeing. It’s crucial to keep in mind that every small change can have a significant impact over a sustained period of time. Be it deciding to take the stairs rather than elevator each day, or just practicing a new skill for 15 min each day. It’s easy to feel disconnected from your surrounding world and not see the environment impact of our actions, but surprisingly as consumers every purchase and consumption decision we make have tremendous environmental consequences. For example just by deciding what we eat throughout the day we can unknowingly be consuming more than 20,000 liters of virtual water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 12 ideas for New Year’s resolutions relate to the environmental topics that we have cover in ResourceLab throughout 2018. These resolutions can be introduced one by one each month, or all at once for the overly ambitious. We hope to not only inspire but provide helpful local resources in Copenhagen to help you along the way. Remember that you don’t have to go at it alone there are great environmentally sustainable projects and communities in Copenhagen you can be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#1 Don’t buy new clothing.&lt;/strong&gt; The fashion industry is the second largest polluter in the world and has a disastrous environmental impact. Thankfully there is tons of second hand clothes out there and most of us already have more clothing than we need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#2 Choose groceries based on environmental footprint.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of us are clueless about how much water and resources it takes to produce 1 kg of produce that we purchase. Surprisingly it can vary greatly, with meat and dairy being most resource intensive. Although going vegan is great, not eating meet just once a week could collectively have a very huge impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#3 Repair before you Replace.&lt;/strong&gt; Due to planned obsolescence so many of our things seem to have a shorter life span forcing us to purchase more. Thankfully initiatives like &lt;a href=&quot;https://repaircafedanmark.dk/&quot;&gt;Repair Cafe&lt;/a&gt; can help you bring back life to your things, events are held monthly both in Nørebro and Valby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#4 Cook meals at home rather than take out.&lt;/strong&gt; When getting takeout we often get much more than food, a whole bag of single use plastic waste. Thru planning meals and cooking ahead you can not only eat healthier but save money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#5 Give away rather than throw out.&lt;/strong&gt; Spending some time to list an item for free rather than just throwing it in the trash, can greatly extend the life span of that object and prevent the purchase of a new one and all of the resource consumption that comes with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#6 Join and support community dinners.&lt;/strong&gt; There are a multiple community dinners held weekly in Copenhagen, that are not only affordable but environmentally sustainable as well. Here are three just to name a few: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/kraftwerket/&quot;&gt;Kraftwerket&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paraplyenfrb.dk/&quot;&gt;CAFÉ PARAPLYEN&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://absaloncph.dk/&quot;&gt;Absalon&lt;/a&gt;. We will be making a complete guide in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#7 Digital Detox.&lt;/strong&gt; The ideas is to stop using all connected devices like your cellphone, computer, tablets and etc. This could be just for 24 hours, weekend, week or a whole month. We as a society have grown dependent on such devices and doing so can help reconnect us with reality. Try the &lt;a href=&quot;https://datadetox.myshadow.org/en/home&quot;&gt;Data Detox&lt;/a&gt; as it can help you also understand how your data is being using by corporations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#8 Detox your home.&lt;/strong&gt;  Household cleaning products are among the most toxic substances and can be absorbed through your skin and give off toxic fumes.  A lot of them can also take a huge toll on the local sewage system. Nowadays there are plenty green alternatives that you can easily buy or make yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#9 Bring your own Bootle, Cup and Bags.&lt;/strong&gt;  Plastic bags are the second most common form of waste after cigarette buds. And each disposable cup, bag and bottle that we consume are mostly made from plastic derived from petroleum. This requires are tremendous amount of oil to produce just for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#10 Offline: 1 day per week away from Social Media.&lt;/strong&gt; Take a day off to spend with your friends, family and loved ones without looking at a screen and rather connecting with those around you that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#11 Hang dry clothing rather than drying.&lt;/strong&gt; Commercial and Residential dryers are one of the most energy consuming appliances. &lt;a href=&quot;http://laundrylist.org/why-line-dry.html&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; are 10 reason why you should hang dry your clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#12 Bike or Walk.&lt;/strong&gt; We are privileged to live Copenhagen were its faster to get most places by bike than any other means of transportation. Walking is so underrated we always rushing to get to the next place rather than taking the time to ponder on the present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/sustainable%20living/pollution/oceans/2019/01/01/new-years-resolutions-to-lower-footprint.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/sustainable%20living/pollution/oceans/2019/01/01/new-years-resolutions-to-lower-footprint.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Sustainable Living</category>
        
        <category>Pollution</category>
        
        <category>Oceans</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Car tires and synthetic clothing are major sources of plastic pollution</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Plastic and its unlimited number of possible applications has led to its broad usage across almost all industries. Plastic is everywhere, penetrating all aspects of everyday life from clothing, transportation, electronics, cleaning products and packaging, just to mention a few. The negative impact of widespread plastic use on our planet has been enormous. The plastic pollution of our environment is staggering, with 9.5 million tonnes of new plastic flowing into our water streams each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there is an increased awareness of the breakdown of plastic over time resulting in micro-plastics that pollute our oceans and water streams, a new publication sheds light on plastics that enter the water already in micro form. The report published by the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) aims to investigate the sources and quantities of such plastic pollution. The report distinguishes between the above mentioned different forms of plastic pollution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary microplastics&lt;/strong&gt; are small plastic particles less than 5 mm in size that are directly released into the environment. These include voluntary addition to products such as shower gels and creams but can also come from the abrasion of large plastic objects such as the erosion of tires while driving or from synthetic textiles when they are washed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondary microplastics&lt;/strong&gt; originate mostly from the degradation of large plastic waste into smaller plastic particles once exposed to the marine environment. Often a result of mismanaged waste such as plastic bags and fishing nets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-sources&quot;&gt;Key sources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seven primary sources of microplastic have been identified based on the data from 4 recently published papers and include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sevensources.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study concluded that between 15 - 31 % of all “plastic soup” in oceans could originate from primary micro plastic sources. This is especial significant for higher income countries equipped with adequate waste treatment facility, where the primary microplastics account for the main contribution of plastic release into the oceans. Almost two thirds of these particles stem from washing synthetic textiles and from tire abrasion. The figure below list the percentage of pollution by source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/globalmicroplastic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Washing synthetic textiles made of polyester, polyethylene, acrylic or elastane, creates primary microplastics through abrasion and shedding of fibers which then discharged in sewage water and potentially end up in the ocean. Tires grind down when used, resulting in tyre dust that either spread by the wind or are washed off the road by rain. The outer parts of the tyre consist of aprox 60% synthetic polymers which are mixed with natural rubber and additives. Surprising the intentional losses through personal care products containing plastic micro-beads only accounts for 2% of global release of primary microplastics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solutions&quot;&gt;Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting the source of the plastic waste requires different sets of solutions. While solution for secondary microplastics include implementing better waste management and reducing the quantities generated, in order to tackle primary microplastics solutions need to focus on product design, infrastructure design and consumer behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-can-you-do&quot;&gt;What can you do&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although manufacturers, designers and governments have to play a major role in implementing solution, as consumers we can do our best to change our behavior in order to minimize our personal impact. You can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop using personal care products that contain microbeads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid the purchase of synthetic textiles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce the use of our personal vehicle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raise awareness among peers and collectively demand companies and governments to take action to implement solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s daunting to realize that even when some people strive to be zero waste, they can still be involuntarily be contributing to the problem. For those interested the full report is available to read for free &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46622&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/plastics/pollution/oceans/2018/10/11/plastic-polution-tires-clothing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/plastics/pollution/oceans/2018/10/11/plastic-polution-tires-clothing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Plastics</category>
        
        <category>Pollution</category>
        
        <category>Oceans</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>More than half of Earth's Wildlife is lost in the past 40 years</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A report released&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plastic and its unlimited number of possible applications has led to its broad usage across almost all industries. Plastic is everywhere, penetrating all aspects of everyday life from clothing, transportation, electronics, cleaning products and packaging, just to mention a few. The negative impact of widespread plastic use on our planet has been enormous. The plastic pollution of our environment is staggering, with 9.5 million tonnes of new plastic flowing into our water streams each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there is an increased awareness of the breakdown of plastic over time resulting in micro-plastics that pollute our oceans and water streams, a new publication sheds light on plastics that enter the water already in micro form. The report published by the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) aims to investigate the sources and quantities of such plastic pollution. The report distinguishes between the above mentioned different forms of plastic pollution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary microplastics&lt;/strong&gt; are small plastic particles less than 5 mm in size that are directly released into the environment. These include voluntary addition to products such as shower gels and creams but can also come from the abrasion of large plastic objects such as the erosion of tires while driving or from synthetic textiles when they are washed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondary microplastics&lt;/strong&gt; originate mostly from the degradation of large plastic waste into smaller plastic particles once exposed to the marine environment. Often a result of mismanaged waste such as plastic bags and fishing nets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-sources&quot;&gt;Key sources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seven primary sources of microplastic have been identified based on the data from 4 recently published papers and include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/sevensources.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study concluded that between 15 - 31 % of all “plastic soup” in oceans could originate from primary micro plastic sources. This is especial significant for higher income countries equipped with adequate waste treatment facility, where the primary microplastics account for the main contribution of plastic release into the oceans. Almost two thirds of these particles stem from washing synthetic textiles and from tire abrasion. The figure below list the percentage of pollution by source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/globalmicroplastic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Washing synthetic textiles made of polyester, polyethylene, acrylic or elastane, creates primary microplastics through abrasion and shedding of fibers which then discharged in sewage water and potentially end up in the ocean. Tires grind down when used, resulting in tyre dust that either spread by the wind or are washed off the road by rain. The outer parts of the tyre consist of aprox 60% synthetic polymers which are mixed with natural rubber and additives. Surprising the intentional losses through personal care products containing plastic micro-beads only accounts for 2% of global release of primary microplastics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solutions&quot;&gt;Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cutting the source of the plastic waste requires different sets of solutions. While solution for secondary microplastics include implementing better waste management and reducing the quantities generated, in order to tackle primary microplastics solutions need to focus on product design, infrastructure design and consumer behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-can-you-do&quot;&gt;What can you do&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although manufacturers, designers and governments have to play a major role in implementing solution, as consumers we can do our best to change our behavior in order to minimize our personal impact. You can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop using personal care products that contain microbeads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid the purchase of synthetic textiles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce the use of our personal vehicle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raise awareness among peers and collectively demand companies and governments to take action to implement solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s daunting to realize that even when some people strive to be zero waste, they can still be involuntarily be contributing to the problem. For those interested the full report is available to read for free &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46622&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wildlife/animals/oceans/2018/09/11/wild-animals-are-gone.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/wildlife/animals/oceans/2018/09/11/wild-animals-are-gone.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Wildlife</category>
        
        <category>Animals</category>
        
        <category>Oceans</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor. If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/06/12/powerful-things-markdown-editor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/06/12/powerful-things-markdown-editor.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/06/12/first-mass-produced.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/06/12/first-mass-produced.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/06/12/education.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/06/12/education.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accumulated experience of social living</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/06/12/acumulated-experience.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/06/12/acumulated-experience.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Bundler</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gem install bundler&lt;/code&gt; installs the bundler gem through RubyGems. You only need to install it once - not every time you create a new Jekyll project. Here are some additional details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundler&lt;/code&gt; is a gem that manages other Ruby gems. It makes sure your gems and gem versions are compatible, and that you have all necessary dependencies each gem requires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; files inform &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; about the gem requirements in your site. If your site doesn’t have these Gemfiles, you can omit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec&lt;/code&gt; and just &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;run jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; uses the gems and versions as specified in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; to ensure your Jekyll site builds with no compatibility or dependency conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about how to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; in your Jekyll project, this tutorial should provide answers to the most common questions and explain how to get up and running quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/05/12/about-bundler.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2018/05/12/about-bundler.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We all wait for summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I engage in the so-called “bull sessions” around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the “brethren” think that education should equip them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that education has a two-fold function to perform in the life of man and in society: the one is utility and the other is culture. Education must enable a man to become more efficient, to achieve with increasing facility the ligitimate goals of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/01/12/we-all-wait-for-summer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/tutorial/2018/01/12/we-all-wait-for-summer.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
